

https://carlossantana3279.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlos3279/ https://github.com/carlossantana3279

## **PROFILE**

I am a *Full-Stack Developer* with 3+ years of paid professional experience. My passion is to create software that improves the lives of its users. I am a diligent worker and a loyal team player. I am committed to continuous self-improvement and have a love of learning.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# DemandHub, Mississauga ON - Full Stack Developer

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- Plan, design, and implement features for front-end web-applications using: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, REACT, Bootstrap
- Plan, design, and implement features for back-end REST API using:
  Javascript, Node.js, MYSQL database, and Redis (NoSQl database), AWS
- Work closely with team members throughout the company (sales, marketing)
- Created and modified more than 10 reporting and analytic pages; Querying millions of records of data daily
- Gave DH a competitive advantage by creating a review invite queuing system used by locations to send out thousands of invites weekly
- Created features using GMB API to sync business hours and collect data
- Made script for marketing team saving over 5 hours of manual labor weekly
- Coded over 10 email templates using EJS that are automated or triggered

### **Bell, Mississauga ON** — Software Developer (Co-op)

MAY 2017 - AUGUST 2018

- Designed, developed, and maintained in-house web tools used by the Core Network Team focused on automation and analytics
- Used HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, C#, .Net Core, MSSQL &
  Postgres databases, Entity Framework, and IIS to create web applications
- Worked in 5-person DevOps team utilizing scrum and agile
- Executed the Scrum Master Role for 6 months (in addition to dev work)
- Successfully designed and facilitated meetings, supervised the scrum process within the team, and ensured that proper processes were followed

# **EDUCATION**

## McMaster University - Computer Science Bachelor's Degree

SEPTEMBER 2014 - MAY 2019, Hamilton ON

- Gained strong knowledge and understanding of Data Structures, Algorithms, and core computer science concepts. Graduated with ~3.70/4.0 GPA (A-)
- Computer Science Society Vice President of Technologies 2016 2017
- Degroot's Den 2018 pitch competition 2nd place Award Winner

# SOFTWARE PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

#### Touch Roulette - Decision Maker

- Android app developed using Corona SDK and Lua
- 1 Million+ downloads on the Google Play Store
- App to help a group of friends make decisions quickly in a fun way

#### **Pillbox**

- Cross platform hybrid app for scheduling and tracking medications
- Built with Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, and .Net Core in a group of 3
- Took the lead on designing Restful API
- Created and used Microsoft OCR API to allow users to take pictures of their prescriptions to automatically enter medications into the app
- Helped deliver 25+ page SRS document

## P0 Compiler

- Designed and implemented a C# recursive descent parser for the P0 language, a proper subset of Pascal, targeting Common Intermediate Language (CIL) assembly code.
- Used **Test-Driven Development (TDD)** to test correctness. (100+ unit tests)
- Created Command-line interface to compile and run P0 programs

# **REFERENCES**

### Roberto Temelkovski

Software Engineer - Bolt Character Reference

### Dylan McIntyre

Software Engineer - Amazon Team Member at Bell

## Dhawal Rank

Lead Full Stack Developer - Briq Team Member at DemandHub

#### Pasindu Gunasekara

Software Engineer - Microsoft Character Reference

Contact information available upon request